A Guide to the Augusta B. Fothergill Westmoreland County Records, 1679-1757
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Augusta B. Fothergill Westmoreland County Records, 1679-1757
The Library of Virginia
21870
35 leaves
Augusta B. Fothergill
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Augusta B. Fothergill, 28 May 1941.
Biographical Information
Augusta Bridgland Middleton Fothergill was born in Lexington, Virginia, 3 February 1876 to John William Middleton (1835-1907) and Sarah Virginia Figgat Middleton (b. 1851). She attended Lexington public schools and received special instruction in literature from professors at the Washington and Lee University. A genealogist and historian, Fothergill authored five books. She was a member of the Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, the American Historical Association, and the Virginia Historical Society. She noted that her first ancestor in Virginia had arrived by 1615. Her husband was Robert Boyer Fothergill. Augusta Fothergill died in Richmond, Virginia, 9 September 1965 and was buried in the family plot in Lexington.
Scope and Content
Westmoreland County, Virginia, records, 1679-1757, compiled by Augusta B. Fothergill (1876-1965) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of deeds for property in Westmoreland County; land grants for property in Westmoreland County and in Northumberland County, Virginia; and judicial records, including bonds, declarations, judgments, suit papers, and writs, from Westmoreland County. Papers also contain the will of Roger Wiggenton of Westmoreland County.
Contents List
- Deed, dated 26 June 1679 and recorded 8 October 1679, for 100 acres in Westmoreland County from Jacob Lucas to Thomas Bee, both of Westmoreland County.
- Deed, dated 20 March 1691 and recorded 21 March 1691, for 100 acres in Westmoreland County from John and Mary Trammell to John Footman, all of Westmoreland County.
- Deed, dated 31 July 1701 and recorded 1 November, for 100 acres in Westmoreland County from Arthur King of Richmond County, Virginia, to James Byard of Westmoreland County.
- Land grant, 21 January 1705, for 26 1/2 acres in Northumberland County, Virginia, from the proprietors of the Northern Neck to William Cornish.
- Will, dated 3 March 1717/18 and recorded 14 August 1718, of Roger Wigginton of Westmoreland County.
- Bond, 4 March 1719/20, from James Byard to Henry Lee, both of Westmoreland County.
- Land grant, 30 March 1727, for 376 acres in Westmoreland Counyt from Thomas, Lord Fairfax to Own Brinham of Westmoreland County.
- Writ, [1741?], from the General Court in Williamsburg, Virginia, to Peter Presly, John Waughton, and John Shapleigh, all of Westmoreland County.
- Bond, dated 14 October 1748 and recorded 5 June 1749, from Benjamin Newton of Prince William County to Richard Lee of Westmoreland County.
- judgment, 24 April 1752, in the suit of John Doe vs William Newton.
- Writ, 6 May [1752?], from the General Court in Williamsburg to Thomas Bennett, sheriff of Westmoreland County.
- Declaration, 1753, by Edmund Pendleton for John Doe against Richard Roe.
- Deed, dated 29 May 1753 and recorded 13 June 1753, for 100 acres in Westmoreland County from Richard Lee to Robert and Joanna Dick of Westmoreland County.
- Deed of lease, dated 30 November 1756 and recorded 2 July 1757, for 116 acres in Westmoreland County from William and Mary Tebbs of Prince William County, Elizabeth McFarlane, John Sorrell, and Judith Sorrell (all of Westmoreland County), and Ann Conway of Lancaster County, Virginia, to Richard Lee.
- Deed of release, dated 1 December 1756 and recorded 2 July 1757, between the Tebbses, the Sorrells, McFarlane, and Lee.
- Suit papers, no date, involving John Pain, probably of Westmoreland County.